GRAHAM NESSLER

FRONT END SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Summary

I am a front-end software engineer with a focus on user experience and user interaction. In my prior career as a published historical scholar and educator, I learned the value of precision, analytical rigor, and adaptability to diverse learning styles and student needs. Now, I add value to organizations by combining these skills with knowledge of a variety of computer languages and technologies.

Projects

FareHarbor Toolkit (with Ryan Westlake)

Github Link

Documentation

This is a powerful tool creator for FareHarbor, an online travel services company. It consists of three tools—a search input tool, a footer tool, and a bottom modal tool—and a config setup (essentially a series of objects) that allows FareHarbor to easily customize these three and other tools for their clients' websites. The project was built to help increase conversions for FareHarbor's clients.

My core contributions: created the search input tool and footer tool; wrote documentation sections on these tools; co-created the config setup; co-authored intro section of documentation.

JavaScript, ExpressJS, Selenium Webdriver, Sketch.

"Flash Shopper"

Github Link

App Link

This is an independent solo project undertaken outside of the Turing School curriculum. It consists of a grocery list where users can enter in an item name, aisle, quantity, and a note. Users can also choose a category (such as "Bread") from a dropdown menu, which will then populate the aisle number (currently for my local King Sooper's). The user can also sort items alphabetically and by aisle number, edit items, and delete items. I recently also added a "pantry" feature with common recurring items that can be added to the list with a single click.

React, Redux, Firebase, JavaScript, SASS/CSS, Webpack.

(For other projects, please see my projects website).

Experience

Florida Atlantic University

Visiting Professor of History

Boca Raton, FL Aug 2015 to May 2016, Aug 2015 to May 2016

Taught courses in United States, Caribbean, Latin American, and global history to around 200 students

Bentley University

Post-Doctoral Fellow

Waltham, MA

Sep 2013 to Jul 2015

Completed book manuscript
 Taught an undergraduate course on dictatorships in modern Latin America

Texas A&M University--Commerce

Commerce, TX

Interim Assistant Professor of History

Aug 2012 to May 2013, Aug 2012 to May 2013

Taught courses in United States and Latin American history at both the graduate and undergraduate levels

Other Interests

Author

Author of book entitled An Islandwide Struggle for Freedom

Revolution, Emancipation, and Reenslavement in Hispaniola, 1789-1809 (University of North Carolina Press, 2016)

Black Belt in Taekwondo

Received in 1995 at Brian Rogers Taekwondo studio, Bryan, Texas.

Contact

gnessler@umich.edu

http://www.grahamnessler.com/

(215) 804-7381 (USA)

Q

y gness1804

in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/graham-nessler-b9025756

O gness1804

Skills

CORE TECHNICAL TOOLBOX

JavaScript/ES6

React/React Router

Redux Ember

iQuery

JSON and Aiax

Agile/Pair Programming

CSS/SASS

HTML5 Canvas

TDD

HTML5

Git/Github

Aysnc JS/Promises

Google Docs

Webpack

Vim

Enzyme and Selenium

Mocha and Chai

Swift

ExpressJS

ADDITIONAL TECHNOLOGIES

Sketch

Atom, Sublime Text

FileMaker

Microsoft Office

Blackboard

i-clickers Pearson eCollege

Turnitin

NON-TECHNICAL SKILLS

Excellent writing skills

Proficient in Spanish, French, and English

Working knowledge of Brazilian Portuguese

Mentoring and leadership

Teaching and public speaking

Teamwork and group collaboration

Education

Turing School of Software and Design Certificate in Front End Engineering 2017

University of Michigan PhD History 2011

College of William and Mary BA History 2005